

IDENTITY STATEMENT

George is a data scientist with more than nine years of product development experience in various industries (Financial Technology, Digital Media, Marketing Technology, Telecommunications). A Scrum practitioner, he advocates for an agile product development approach to data science and analytics.

KEY SKILLS

- Product Development
- Project Management
- Agile Methodologies (Scrum)
- Data Strategy
- Data Visualization and Storytelling
- Data Mining
- Natural Language Processing
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Cloud Computing
- Network Science

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Python
- SQL
- Tableau
- Gephi
- Selenium
- Orange
- Amazon Web Services
- Apache Spark
- Microsoft Office
- Google Suite

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

AWARDS/HONORS

- Most Outstanding M.S. Graduate of the U.P. College of Science (2009)
- Most Outstanding B.S. Applied Physics Graduate, U.P. Diliman (2007)
 Magna Cum Laude, U.P. Diliman
- Magna Cum Laude, U.P. Dilimai (GWA 1.262/1.000)
- U.P. Oblation Scholarship (2002)
- DOST-SEI Merit Scholarship (2002)

PUBLICATIONS

- Esleta, G. A., & Monterola, C. (2009). Effect of memory and reinforcement on the propagation and morphology of fracture in a two-dimensional mass-spring system. International Journal of Modern Physics C, 20(07).
- Esleta, G. A., & Monterola, C. (2008). Structural reinforcement in a spring-block model of stress-induced fracture propagation. Computer Physics Communications 178(9).

GEORGE ALLAN PEREZ ESLETA

DATA SCIENCE | DATA ANALYTICS | AGILE PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT

in linkedin.com/in/gpesleta

gesleta@aim.edu

+639298874852

EDUCATION

2019-Present MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DATA SCIENCE

Asian Institute of ManagementDate of Graduation: July 2020

Capstone Project: PROPeLR: A Proprietary Lead Scoring and

Recommender System

2007-2009 MASTER OF SCIENCE IN PHYSICS

University of the Philippines Diliman

April 2009

2002-2007 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN APPLIED PHYSICS

University of the Philippines Diliman

April 2007

WORK EXPERIENCE

VOYAGER INNOVATIONS, INC. (digital innovations arm of the PLDT Group) 2017-2019

Senior Product Development Specialist

Responsibilities: Product Development, Data Privacy Compliance

- Led the ideation and product development of the enhanced know-your-customer (KYC) process of PayMaya. The user experience was streamlined by replacing the inapp video call with a video recording, resulting in reduced approval time and improved operational efficiency.
- Centralized monitoring of customer consent and opt-ins for the Voyager Group by leading the product development and deployment of a consent platform and integrating it will all consumer touchpoints.

VOYAGER INNOVATIONS, INC. (digital innovations arm of the PLDT Group) 2016-2017

Senior Analytics Lead

Responsibilities: Data Analytics, Data Strategy, Data Privacy Compliance

- Managed Voyager's data privacy compliance program and acted as the group's point
 of contact with the PLDT Group Data Privacy Council, helping Voyager achieve one of
 the highest compliance rates among PLDT and its subsidiaries.
- Consolidated the data sources of the various business units and created a single source of truth by formulating the data warehousing strategy and coordinating with IT and Engineering teams for its implementation.
- Automated the reporting requirements of the Finance department and the Management Committee by spearheading the development of management dashboards using Tableau.

SMART COMMUNICATIONS, INC.

2014-2016

Product Development Lead

Responsibilities: Product Development and Management

- Increased the digital presence of the noontime television show *Eat Bulaga!* by leading the product development and successful launch of *Eat Bulaga! Mobile*, rated as the Top Free Entertainment application in Google Play Store for eight consecutive weeks with more than 500,000 downloads and 10,000 monthly active users.
- Provided support to TV5's coverage of the 2016 Philippine elections by leading the
 product development of the survey platform that powered the Bilang Pilipino-SWS
 mobile survey. This pioneering project tracks the opinions of a statistically
 representative panel of voters via mobile phones and provides results in 24 hours.



IDENTITY STATEMENT

George is a data scientist with more than nine years of product development experience in various industries (Financial Technology, Digital Media, Marketing Technology, Telecommunications). A Scrum practitioner, he advocates for an agile product development approach to data science and analytics.

KEY SKILLS

- Product Development
- Project Management
- Agile Methodologies (Scrum)
- Data Strategy
- Data Visualization and Storytelling
- Data Mining
- Natural Language Processing
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Cloud Computing
- Network Science

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Python
- SQL
- Tableau
- Gephi
- SeleniumOrange
- Amazon Web Services
- Apache Spark
- Microsoft Office
- Google Suite

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

AWARDS/HONORS

- Most Outstanding M.S. Graduate of the U.P. College of Science (2009)
- Most Outstanding B.S. Applied Physics Graduate, U.P. Diliman (2007)
 Magna Cum Laude J.P. Diliman
- Magna Cum Laude, U.P. Diliman (GWA 1.262/1.000)
- U.P. Oblation Scholarship (2002)
- DOST-SEI Merit Scholarship (2002)

PUBLICATIONS

- Esleta, G. A., & Monterola, C. (2009). Effect of memory and reinforcement on the propagation and morphology of fracture in a two-dimensional mass-spring system. International Journal of Modern Physics C, 20(07).
- Esleta, G. A., & Monterola, C. (2008). Structural reinforcement in a spring-block model of stress-induced fracture propagation. Computer Physics Communications 178(9).

GEORGE ALLAN PEREZ ESLETA

DATA SCIENCE | DATA ANALYTICS | AGILE PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT

in linkedin.com/in/gpesleta

✓ gesleta@aim.edu

T +639298874852

WORK EXPERIENCE

SMART COMMUNICATIONS. INC.

Senior Business Analyst

Responsibilities: Business Analysis, Project Management (via Scrum),

 Quality Assurance
 Coordinated with original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) for the handset and firmware requirements of the Smart Netphone, the world's first smartphone backed by a telecom operator-managed platform.

- Facilitated backlog grooming and sprint planning sessions for SmartNet, an over-the-top (OTT) mobile application based on the Smart Netphone.
- As interim Quality Assurance Lead, supervised a team of four quality assurance analysts to ensure that all app releases have no critical issues before publishing to the app store.

AZEUS SYSTEMS PHILIPPINES LIMITED

2009-2010

2010-2013

Software Developer

UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES DILIMAN

2007-2009

Instructor

DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

PROPeLR: A Proprietary Lead Scoring and Recommender System

 Developed an Al-enabled lead scoring model and a service recommender for a Philippine-based website design and development company to assist its sales team in sales lead prioritization and cross-selling of new services to existing accounts.

Capturing Collaboration in the Philippine House of Representatives under the Duterte Administration

Uncovered underlying communities in the 17th and 18th Session of the Philippine
House of Representatives by analyzing the bill co-authorship network using network
science techniques.

SADDR: System for Automated Detection of Diabetic Retinopathy

• Developed a system that uses a deep learning model to predict the severity of diabetic retinopathy from retinal images with 90% accuracy.

Airbnbnb: Where is your next destination?

 Developed a destination recommender system that suggests a user's next destination based on previous Airbnb bookings using a combination of association rule mining and collaborative filtering.

UnwRappler: Predicting Mood and Polarity of Rappler Articles

 Used natural language processing and supervised machine learning algorithms to develop a classification model that predicts the dominant mood and polarity of Rappler news articles with 72% accuracy.

UnwRappler: Identifying Themes in Rappler News Articles

 Uncovered the underlying themes of Rappler news articles published from January 2018 to May 2019 using natural language processing and unsupervised clustering.